hello and welcome to big deal it
almost seemed like a 2020 match in the
second
half of this year when deal activity
really picked up
catalyzed by a gush of liquidity fueling
the equity markets and also the pandemic
disruptions
giving new opportunities in times of
adversity
now deals with 80 billion dollars
clocked in and top deals from new pools
of capital
really lined up in india global giants
like facebook google
and market private equity firms they
joined reliance's
fundraising plan which was nothing short
of a spectacle so those were the
highlights of 2020
and solving for debt concerns really
continued to be a key driver
for most of the deals and private equity
investors
also spotted value creators
with an eagle eye and we saw many buyout
transactions as well
but the new year well that brings in new
avenues
which are opening up to tap global funds
so what's in store for that and what are
the learnings
from 2020 let's find out from none other
than zya modi of azvn partners
ziya it's always good to have you on
cnbc tv 18.
pleasure speaking to you and it's so
refreshing to see you outdoors as well
you're definitely holidaying unlike us
how will you remember 2020
personally as well as professionally
so i think uh and thank you nisha for
having me on this show
and uh happy new year in advance i think
that
for for many of us the roller coaster
ride was
pretty much the same i think when kovid
attacked
the world in march uh
all of us froze partially uh just uh
in a state of uh uncertainty as to what
the pathway forward would be um i think
personally for myself obviously uh
worried about the firm
its revenues top line what sort of
business we could expect to continue
with what would fall away
uh what was the pipeline that had to
kept going but i think from a
from a business point of view from our
clients point of view what we've seen
is that uh people have sort of digested
uh what uh covet has meant to each
business
and to each one personally yes and the
last quarter
has certainly been more stick both in
terms of
perception as well as in terms of the
deal activity that we've seen
so i would say started off in a
semi-paralyzed way but
uh end of year pretty much dealt with
how to cope with it for the most part
that's why i called it uh
yes that's why i called it 2020 or
towards the end
because it was looking like deal street
was trying to overcompensate for the
rest of the year which was largely dead
uh but
uh zia as far as the recovery mode is
concerned
uh the overall sentiment is concerned
you have an interface with not just
your business houses in the country but
also the global investors the private
equity
investors so you have a very big canvas
of understanding how do you see this
recovery
and therefore the sentiment for business
so uh from a from a azp firm point of
view
we uh started uh covid with uh reliance
jio
so uh it was completely virtual
it was an amazing uh exercise and
the orchestration by the reliance team
led
largely by manoj modi and of course
mukesh
was impeccable so we saw the largest fdi
coming to the country
20 billion and as you say marquee
private equity players completely
believing in the jio story
and in digital india but that was more
the exception
we saw private equity hunker down we saw
deals get delayed
we saw our country heads complaining to
us by saying when they went to their ic
committees
the ic committee said don't you know
this covid
go back for a lower valuation from the
promoters
the promoters of course in varying
stages of capital requirement
and not wanting to sell out cheap so
very interesting dynamics
at that time uh we also saw
as you rightly pointed out a huge amount
of
raising of capital so early the start of
the year we saw
uh we did access icici htfc and of
course the 7 billion
reliance rights issue one after the
other so you could see that
the market was still willing to give
money to
top class players and i think quality
was then the absolute requirement for
people to write a check
at that time but now you've seen how the
stock market has surged which
is really counter intuitive to if you
think there is a covert depression
and we see now because there is so much
dry powder
uh in the pe firms that they are
looking at india again in the last
quarter at least
extremely actively so i would say that
uh
the end of the calendar year has not
been as bad
as you would have thought when you
started off
with the calamity of kovid in april
and i think that that trend according to
me will come to it
when you talk about 2021 will continue
so we see now suddenly
more term sheets being exchanged more
tired more bids
coming into the market i think for a
long time
private equity just didn't feel
comfortable
uh introducing new deals into their
system when they hadn't even shaken
hands or
been in the same room as the promoter
and i think that's now all changing and
since
everything's opening up a bit we see
activity coming back
that's right azia in fact deleveraging
has been
one of the most important driving
factors
in the covert times and in fact the big
business houses have realized that
and therefore the massive fundraising
exercise as well
but do you not think that it is the
survival of the fittest and it's only
the choice few who got more money and
the actual ones who really require it
right now
to sail through is the market so
conducive that even
they are going to get the funds it
depends
i think that you know uh earlier you saw
only uh the really quality marquee
houses who could attract money
i think that there will be an expansion
of that circle now
simply because money has to flow into
something and it can't
keep flowing into the same uh businesses
and the same houses
uh forever so private equity will have
to expand banks
uh will have to lend to more than aaa
clients
and if you look at what happened in 2020
in the banking space nisha the classic
one was
the yes bank restructuring for us as a
firm it was a huge learning exercise
the interaction with the reserve bank
the administrator
the former management the new management
rights
uh everybody as investors trying to see
how attractive this would be in the in
the mid to long term
so the banking industry you look at lvb
and dv
and dbs uh i think that is going to see
changes the reserve bank is going to
look at cooperative banks
uh much more strictly and with that sort
of cleanup and that sort of
restructuring
and the market requiring india requiring
more financing and you see all these
stressed houses
uh coming in to take out uh existing
nbfcs indian nbfcs who need to be taken
out
simply because they can't they don't
have the staying power so you see a lot
of foreign capital coming in as well
on debt restructuring all right we'll
talk
more in depth about what uh the 2021
outlook and crystal gazing really looked
like it looks like
but yeah i wanted to understand what are
the most
important changes that you have seen
because of covert 19
in 2020 which is going to have a long
lasting impact
so obviously outside the law the the
biggest change i've seen is
just the digital learning across all
businesses and service providers
and i think that to some extent the way
the world will work
in india will have changed uh to some
extent
now how much and for how long and how
permanent the change will be is to be
seen
but clearly the the mind space has
shifted
into from the traditional way of working
to a
much more flexible way of working if you
like
in terms of uh takeaways of 2020
i think that personally what i saw
was the ability of some of the
regulators
to really quickly react uh to market
realities and market pain points
and in particular my interaction with
sebby
has been so satisfying because
every time i would see that there was a
logical pain point that needed
addressing
really a couple of phone calls achieved
the desired effect of at least
conveying the pain point what the
regulator did or did not do was his
domain or his prerogative
but the ability to listen the openness
of communication
both with the uh reserve bank
and with sebi i found particularly
satisfying
and if you look at the way the changes
were made
uh small ones uh reducing uh
unnecessary uh interaction between
regulators which were inconsistent
you look at how they eased the capital
raising issue
the the the directions for the rights
programs
and the mca the ministry of corporate
affairs
kept passing enabling regulations and
circulars
to allow uh paperwork not to drown
what was already a very difficult
situation so i would say
not really any big bang stuff but
certainly constant incremental changes
to reduce
pain points some knee jerk reactions as
well
uh during covet but i would think much
better
half of the glass was much more full
than empty
all right so that's definitely positive
thinking ziya modi
and uh clearly agility as well as the
online solutions
and also giving operational capability
with social distancing have been some of
the key highlights of the business
community and they've dealt with it but
we'll slip into a short breather on big
deal
but we'll continue the chat with zia
modi and we will focus
on the outlook 2021 when it comes to the
deal street stay tuned
welcome back you're watching big deal
and we are in conversation with cr modi
on the future outlook in terms of the
deal street in the new year 2021.
uh so we were talking about the various
um
learnings in 2020 but what are the most
important deal trends that you're
picking
up for 2021 which we are bracing up for
now so i think that
uh private equity is going to come back
very strongly
as i said earlier it's simply because of
the dry powder that
they have with them and their global
fundraising even in covet times has gone
extremely well
so asia and india will certainly be a
focus of
investment activity i think that uh you
know they will continue to look for
not only good value but also the sectors
which they see
are going to be important for india so
you continue to see
a huge amount of interest in financial
services
uh nbfcs banking and of course
pharma and healthcare has taken uh
prime space uh even in 2020.
i also see the the mind mind shift
to many more control deals as opposed to
uh significant minorities earlier uh you
know five to
seven years ago you had a thousand
questions coming from private equity as
to
what would happen if they had to make a
takeover offer if they were classified
as promoters
uh how often would they have to worry
about going to jail
i think that mind shift has now gone
into the fact that we need to control
our destiny
and we're willing to pay the premium to
get control and we are willing to go
through the takeover offer
and comply with the listing requirements
that sebi requires so
a lot of control activity i think will
happen
in 2021 as well logistics
and warehousing and other sectors will
drive
and we also see real estate uh picking
up you've seen
so many of the recent deals announced
where foreign
private equity has come in platforms
have been created with indian
real estate houses so overall i think
2021 should definitely be
a year where at least i am personally
not too worried about uh deal making
right uh there'll be enough and more
action and zio were mentioning about
real estate yes
brookfield and blackstone together have
i think captured a lion's share
of the real estate assets and more deals
could be also in the pipeline
but what i also wanted to understand and
just playing the devil's advocate here
is that yes we have already seen the
semblance of
buyout deals by the private equity firms
in the in this year and that will
continue
but what about the market valuations
we've hit 14 000
ah on nifty already and private equity
is a
value picker and exits also define
whether they want to enter at this point
so uh we still have to see the exit
point of view when it comes to the
buyout successes
that's still to be seen and in that
scenario the markets are hotting up
what do you see in the short term then
if the market valuations are high
so i'm seeing two trends in fact i was
just talking to
the country head of one of my uh large
uh
private equity clients yesterday and he
was telling me that uh
they see the values as too hot and
therefore they
are waiting and taking a deep breath so
that's
one way of looking at it the other way
is where other private equity investors
are quite happy
even today to jump into bidding
situations
and to make sure that uh you know they
win and when you have a bid situation as
you know
uh nation the valuations are always
higher than
if you had an exclusive and you were
negotiating one-on-one
but those deals are still happening and
i think it's a combination of
perhaps a longer-term view of india
and its growth uh and putting covet
behind them
uh and saying okay the last the effect
may last a couple of years
but we are here for the longer term and
also realizing
that frankly with all the dry powder
that each one of them has
i mean how many deals are there right
they're not a thousand deals
that you can say i let this one go to
every one of them if the price is high
so private equity is having to pay more
value than they would like
uh they try to shave it down as much as
possible but i think uh
the the traction is uh definitely going
to continue in 2021
the ask of the promoter in a bidding
context
versus the private equity not wanting to
lose too many deals
that's right but also private equity has
played the role of
giving capital and rescuing some of the
companies from the debt situations as
well
which earlier used to be the forte of
other promoters
and other strategic players and we used
to see more consolidation than private
equity so this is a big trend that
really picked up
but we did see one large transaction in
future retail
but bought over by reliance retail where
the debt situation was solved
for by another strategic do you think
that
the promoters the corporates have the
fire power
for more consolidation or buying out
other companies which are not doing well
not many would i think frankly i mean if
you take away
the business houses like the tatas and
reliance
very few would have the firepower to
write very large checks
and i think that is what has changed
what earlier could be resolved with a
reasonable uh check size now
the check size to rescue a firm or to
put
a business back on track has become much
larger
and that is why you see all these
special sits funds
coming in to try and see what value they
can derive
and what discount they can get and yet
uh make sure that the the guy that
they've taken out
is not on the street otherwise the deal
won't happen you see ibc which has been
suspended
of course but that's coming back right
in april
so you will see other deals that come to
the table as a result of
ibc being revitalized and there again
will be opportunities
both for special seats as well as for
private equity and some strategics
uh to come in and to bid for assets
which are on the block
you see a lot of power companies that
were in stress uh
those will be back on the block uh in
april
uh many of them and similarly large
large manufacturing companies that could
not survive covet
as much as they would have liked to will
again be struggling because
you know at that stage the banks again
will be forced to put them into ibc
so if you look at how dfl uh dhfl is
playing out
uh that's a story in itself right
that's got bidders uh who when they were
put to the test
increased their bids and the starting
bid
and the uh hopefully the closing bids
are going to be
uh quite different for the benefit of
the banks so i think they
they will still up their price if it's a
bidding contest misha
all right and we have had many learnings
from the ibc
process and many hits and misses so many
learnings
will now define the future cause of
action there
but what about the role of the regulator
and the government
what are the key reforms which are
really required for ease of deal-making
ease of attracting fdi and flows into
the countries here
a couple of things i think that you know
what set back everybody
in terms of fdi was the uh press note 3
that the government had introduced in
terms of
uh needing approval of uh investments
from neighboring companies
countries and primarily the neighboring
country in focus would have been china
and i think the the lack of clarity as
to what are the brightline tests out
there
put many deals on hold or delay them
i think there's a market practice that
has developed
but i think that you know the government
would do well to formalize
what their thinking is in terms of uh
china investment because it is not just
direct china investment
but it also flows through indirectly and
so if you look at many private equity
firms
who have chinese lps and
large chinese lps who have invested
across the board in many significant
private equity houses
how do those get treated uh how
unwelcome then
is the uh investment by the private
equity
company itself and you know even if you
go for approval
uh the other thing that i think the
government would be well advised to do
is to speed up the approval process i
think there are over 100 applications
under press note 3 and i mean i may be
wrong but i'm not sure if any of them
have really gotten approved
so what is the streamlining of this
which results in an
outcome if you look at other regulators
for example you take a competition
commission which we deal with all the
time
even during covet earlier uh they did
not have virtual hearings because they
were worried about confidentiality
but then they enabled technology to deal
with that
so today deal making is not getting
stopped
by any regulator really i think when the
chinese question comes up that is when
press note 3 has to be
facilitated i agree with you it has to
come up
and and make it easier for for india no
this has been a pain point and the
entire industry has spoken about
it so hopefully we will get some
resolution and clarity
on that front in 2021 and also global
direct listing
norms those also are something that the
whole industry is waiting for
but modi thank you so much uh for
joining us with the wealth of knowledge
and uh look forward to meeting you in
2021 and have a great year
uh to you and asidb and partners from
cnbc tv
2021 to all of you thank you thank you
so much thanks for joining us
so that was zia modi with her views on
the deal street there are a few
aspects which are going to drive uh the
m a transaction as well as the private
equity transactions in 2021 as well
but tackling debt as well as raising
fund for growth
are going to be the prime focus on the
deal street next year have a great year
happy new year to all our viewers from
cnbc tv 18 thanks so much
for tuning in
you